What do you get for the man who has everything...?
The Game is a drama, thriller, mystery film directed by David Fincher.
In honor of his birthday, San Francisco banker Nicholas Van Orton, a financial genius and a cold-hearted loner, receives
an unusual present from his younger brother, Conrad: a gift certificate to play a unique kind of game.
In nary a nanosecond, Nicholas finds himself consumed by a dangerous set of ever-changing
rules, unable to distinguish where the charade ends and reality begins.
Nicholas Van Orton, played by Michael Douglas.
Conrad Van Orton, played by Sean Penn.
Christine, played by Deborah Kara Unger.
Jim Feingold, played by James Rebhorn.
Samuel Sutherland, played by Peter Donat.
Ilsa, played by Carroll Baker.
The Game is a 1997 American mystery thriller film directed by David Fincher, starring Michael Douglas, Sean Penn,
Deborah Kara Unger and James Rebhorn and produced by Propaganda Films and PolyGram Filmed Entertainment.
It tells the story of a wealthy investment banker who is given a mysterious birthday gift by his
brother—participation in a game that integrates in strange ways with his everyday life.
As the lines between the banker's real life and the game become more
uncertain, hints of a larger conspiracy begin to unfold.
The Game was well received by critics like Roger Ebert and major periodicals like The New York Times, but had
middling box-office returns compared to the success of Fincher's previous film Se7en (1995).
The film later gained a strong following among Fincher's fans,
with some noting it as one of his best films.
The film explores themes of san francisco, california,
manipulation, danger of life, puzzle, birthday present.
The tone is mind_bending and emotional and intense.